Hello.
In this next lecture, we're going to go over how to make our boss attack our player character with
a ranged projectile attack.
If we open up our boss blueprint and right click in some free space and look for event again players
and then they can play.
We're going to set a timer by event.
And just right click on this return buddy and promote it to a rival and call this boss attack event.
Check this looping box and for the time right click and go random float in range and for the minimum
value put two and for the max value, put four and just connect this to time.
So every 2 to 4 seconds will make our boss attack our player character.
Drag up this event and look for add custom event calls.
Play boss Attack animation.
Next.
If we just close this and go over to our Boss animation blueprint, we're going to create a jump node.
But whenever our boss attacks our player character, so if we right click and go jump and just call
this attack.
We can drag off and look for, Animation said.
And I'm just going to rename this to my boss attack.
We can head inside here and make this play our boss attack animation.
And if we connect from bots attack to idle.
Once our bots attack, animation has finished playing or enter our idle animation or head inside here
and right click and look for time remaining post-attack when the time remaining of this animation is
less than 0.0 1 seconds, I will transition back into my idle animation.
If we go back to our past blueprint.
We can now drag in our animation component.
And try and get, for instance.
And from here we can cool the jump to Node.
For the jump name.
I called it Attack.
And we can just connect this into here and go compile and play.
So every 2 to 4 seconds, my posture swing it sort.
The next thing we're going to do is make it so that when our boss swings, it sort of projectile will
spawn, which is aimed at our player character.
If we close this and go over to our boss animation source, find people, attack animation and go to
frame around here, frame three around here, we're going to right click and go add, notify new, notify
and call this boss attack.
So around this frame, we're going to call a custom event inside of our player character.
So if I right click and go add custom event and call this attack.
If we go over to the viewport, go ahead and look for a scene and just rename this to our projectile
spawn location.
And place this roughly around where our boss swings its sword in that animation.
So I think around here is fine.
Next.
If we go back to the Bancroft when we call this attack event, we're going to make our projectiles ball
location based or player character.
Then we're going to spawn a projectile at that location.
So in order to make this place our player character, we can right click and look for find, look at
rotation.
But the start just right click and look.
We'll get actor location and connect this into here for the target right click and look for get player
character.
From here we can drag up and get actor location.
So what this node will do is it'll get the location of our boss and the location of our player character.
And this return value will be a value pointed towards our player character.
So if we drag in our project hotspot location and drag up here and look for set world rotation and connect
this into here, this will make our projectile spawn location be facing towards our player character.
After we do this, we're going to drag and look for spawn actor from class.
And if we just briefly close this and go to our mushroom folder and find the mushroom project, I'll
just copy this and paste this again in our Boss Blueprint folder.
Right click and rename it our Boss project.
If we open it up and go to the viewport, set the paper flipbook and change it to be the sort flipbook
that we made earlier.
And I'm going to scale up a bit, so make it seven and also just adjust the sphere.
Then if we go over to the bank of.
And go to this bit where we make our projectile damage the player character and then explode.
For this we want to replace this with the saw explosion sprite.
So this one saw destroyed.
Then we can go compile and go back to our boss blueprint.
And this is the projectile that we're going to spawn.
So I look for both predictor and for the spawn transform.
Just track in our product, our sport location and drive up here and look for that world transform.
This will get the location, rotation and scale of this object.
And then if we just connect attack into here and go back to our animation blueprint, we can go over
to functions and set the boss attack.
Now, if I drag in my boss VP reference and drag off and call the attack customer event.
I go compile and save when my boss now swings its hoard.
It should spawn a projectile which is aiming towards the player character.
If I could play.
And let's test this out.
So the pot bellied Twinkie thought it's going to projectile, which is aimed towards me.
There's one more thing we need to do, and that is select our level and just give this the tag.
Of wool and the tag of level.
That way the projectile will collide with the walls of this level.
So if I could play it, my boss besides me, the projectile should still be destroyed.